Sanjeev Kumar

Software Engineer

Enthusiastic IT professional in building scripts and managing databases with 2.5 year of work experience. I have a range of technical skills and interpersonal skills that enable me to interact with a wide range of clients. Aim to learn, work and achieve more in IT field.

sk814@student.le.ac.uk

+44 7774081892

22 Norman street, Leicester, UK 💡

linkedin.com/in/sanjeev-singh1 in

github.com/sk814 (7)

stackoverflow.com/users/12935570

WORK EXPERIENCE

ETL DevOps

Gemini solutions Private Limited

07/2017 - Present Guruqram, Harvana, India IT Consulting and Product Development firm (Client – PIMCO, US) Major Role/Projects:

- Maintaining existing processes, Data Warehousing, Automation of daily tasks, FTP/SFTP files loading/ uploading
- Extracting financial data from different vendors with various sources and load it into the Databases using scripts.
- Designed OuervSurge reports to catch issues in data set.
- Designed tools using python and bash scripting for reporting and daily usage of Team.
- Creating/Maintaining metadata entries through Alation/Database

Internship

Prezotech Solutions Private Limited

11/2016 - 03/2017

Major role/Project:

Software and Barcode Manufacturer firm

- Managing stock of Barcode Printers, labels, bio metric and scanners
- Developed a windows based software for inventory management using Java and H2 database.
- Maintaining/Enhancing metadata entries

EDUCATION

MSc in Cloud Computing

University of Leicester, UK

01/2020 - Present Leicester

Computer Science Engineering

A.P.J Abdul kalam Technical University, India

06/2014 - 04/2017

India 72% (1st ("First Class"))

Polytechnic in CSE

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education, India

06/2011 - 04/2014

India,77%1st ("First Class")

D.A.V Public School (CBSE Board), India

SKILLS

Autosys SOL Shell scripting Python scripting Bloomberg DL and Terminal JIRA, TeamForge, Pagerduty, Servicenow SVN QuerySurge **SNOW** Alation

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Event Management

- Worked on back end designing and implementation using MySQL of a web application developed to store and manage the attendance and other details of the guests attending the events organised by mediator.
- Used in 4 live events and has future scope as well.
- Stored data can downloaded in excel format and can be used for reporting.

Mail Automation

Delhi

- Developed a Python script to send wishes to the list of clients and vendors on festivals.
- Used by Prezotech Solution Pvt. Ltd, Delhi to send automated mail wishes on selected holidays.

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent) Hindi (Native language)

VOLUNTEERING

- Light Up Leicester 2020 (By Art Reach)
- Peer Mentor (University of Leicester student union)
- Primary School Reading (Student and Academic Services)

INTERESTS

